sumra.net 2017-06-06

# Sumra Marketplace |

1 .This Privacy Policy concerns the information we collect about you and how we do it

To provide you with our products and services, we may need information about you.

If you use our websites, you are in control of what information we collect about you, but if you choose not to share your information, you may not be able to access or use some areas of our websites.

1a) How we collect information about you

We will collect information about you when you:

  * use our online services;
  * click on one of the adverts that we put on other websites;
  * ask for information from us;
  * give us a testimonial or other feedback;
  * submit comments relating to blogs or articles featured on our website or a website belonging to one of our affiliates;
  * enter competitions or special promotions; or
  * fill in surveys.

We may also get information about you from third parties, with whom we have a business relationship.

1b) What information we collect

The information we collect and hold about you may include your:

  * name;
  * phone and/or mobile phone numbers;
  * email address;
  * IP address;
  * search criteria, including businesses and locations searched;
  * purchase history;
  * date of birth;
  * password details, answers to security questions (for example your mother's maiden name) or both; and
  * any other information you may give us when you write to us or contact us in other ways.

1c) Why we need your email address

When you register on our websites, we collect your email address. We may use it for account administration (for example to email you your password, if you forget it) and for added security. We may use your email address to send you a confirmation of any application you make, if you buy any product or service from or through us, to confirm any profile changes you make and to respond to you if you contact us for information about our services. We might also use your email address to bring you news such as changes to the way you can use our online services or new services and special offers we think you might be interested in.

1d) Using cookies or other on-device storage

Cookies are information files stored on your computer that help websites remember you. We and our partners collect information about your use of our websites through cookies.

1e) Recording your calls

We may record or monitor calls that you receive from us, or make to us. We do this for security and training purposes and to improve the service we provide to you.

2\. How we will use information we collect about you

Whenever you give us your personal information, legally we have to use it in accordance with the terms of various privacy laws, including the Data Protection Act 1998 (we refer to these laws in this privacy policy as the 'privacy laws').

2a) When you use our websites

When you give us information while using our websites, we will use it for the purposes set out in this privacy policy, on the data entry forms, in any relevant terms or conditions and on pages or emails which link to the data entry forms.

This information does not allow us to identify you. We collect it from lots of visitors to our websites and analyse it. This lets us build up a picture of how people use our websites. This helps us improve the services we offer.

We may also give anonymous statistics about users to other, reputable organisations, but the information we provide will not include details that would allow these organisations to identify you.

2b) Customisation of our online services and advert targeting

We may use the information you give us about yourself when you register on or for our online services, or the information we collect via cookies when you use our online services to build up a picture of your interests. We may then use this information to try to make sure that when you visit our websites or use our online services, you don't miss offers and information that might interest you. This is called advert targeting or interest based advertising.

2c) Tracking how our online services are used

We may collect information about activity on our online services, or we may use other organisations to collect it and to share the results with us. We use this information to:

  * analyse statistics;
  * track pages and paths used by visitors to, or users of, our online service;
  * target the adverts or offers, such as banners, on our online services and on the websites and other online services of other organisations; and
  * track the use of our internet banner adverts and other links from our marketing partners' websites to our websites.

For these purposes, we and the other organisations we use keep information on the path you take to get to our online services and on some of the pages you visit or use through our online services, using cookies, web beacons and other on-device storage. You cannot be personally identified from the information that we or these other organisations collect. For information about web beacons, or the organisation we use (including how to decline their cookies), please read our Cookie Policy.

2d) Commercial use of data

From time to time the company may ask you for permission to use your data commercially. If you give us this right then we will use your data and share it with carefully selected third parties who will be bound by certain restraints imposed on them by the company at the time of the transaction.

2e) Testimonials

If you give us feedback, we may use it to improve our products and services and we may publish it online or offline to promote our business, products and services. We will ask for your permission before we publish it.

2f) Comments submitted to our online blogs and articles

If you wish to submit a comment or feedback on a blog or article featured on our website, we may (but are not obliged to) publish your comment online or offline to promote our business, products and services. We will collect your name which will be displayed next to your comment, and e-mail address, which will not be published, but which we may use to contact you in relation to your comment.

2g) Direct marketing

For information on how we may market to you, please read section 4 - Direct marketing and how you can change your marketing preferences.

2h) User surveys

Every now and again, we may ask you for your opinion on our products and services. When we do surveys we may use cookies or other on-device storage and may combine the information collected by those cookies or other on-device storage with your answers. We will make sure that the survey results do not identify you, or anyone else who fills in our surveys.

3\. When we contact you

We may contact you:

  * about information you have asked for, in order to answer your request;
  * if you have given us feedback, to discuss that feedback or ask your permission to publish it;
  * if you have chosen to receive further information from us;
  * to invite you to take part in surveys about our products and services (it is always up to you whether you want to take part);
  * for marketing purposes, unless you tell us to stop

4\. Direct marketing and how you can manage your marketing preferences

From time to time we may offer you the chance to receive important news from our group and information about our products and services, such as changes to the way you can use our online services or new services and special offers you might be interested in.

We will ask you if you want to receive direct marketing if you register for one of our services; or enter a competition or register for a promotion with any company in our group.

Unless you tell us otherwise, we may contact you by phone, post, email, text message or any other way (electronic or otherwise). We will normally send you direct marketing by email if we have your email address.

If you would like us to stop sending direct marketing to you, we offer simple ways for you to tell us to stop. Whenever you receive direct marketing from us, we will tell you how to unsubscribe.

If you tell us that you do not want to receive direct marketing, we will still contact you in order to provide you with services you request and for administration purposes.

5\. Who we may share your personal information with

We may need to share your information with other organisations to provide you with the products, services or information you ask for. We may pass your information to one or more of the following organisations:

  * other companies in our group;
  * data processing companies, mailing houses and other third party suppliers working on our behalf;
  * government and enforcement agencies, such as Trading Standards and the police.

Every now and again, we receive requests for information from government departments, the police and other enforcement agencies. If this happens, and there is a proper legal basis for providing your personal information, we will provide it to the organisation asking for it.

6\. Where we process your personal information

When we use your information as described in section 2 - How we will use information we collect about you, this may occasionally involve sending your information outside the European Economic Area (EEA). Where we do this, we make sure that appropriate steps are taken to protect your personal information and your rights. By providing us with your personal information, you agree that we may transfer, store and process your information outside the EEA.

7\. How we keep your information secure

We take the security of your personal information very seriously. We have put in place technology and security policies which are designed to protect the personal information that we hold about you. We also follow the strict security procedures that privacy laws require. These cover storing, using and releasing any information you have provided, and preventing unauthorised access or use.

8\. Why we link to other websites

Our online services contain hyperlinks to websites that are owned and operated by other organisations. These websites have their own privacy and cookie policies, and we urge you to read them. They control how your personal information is used when you give it to these other organisations or they collect it with cookies. We do not approve any other websites and we are not responsible for any information, material, products or services that are on or accessible through those websites or for the privacy practices of websites run by other organisations. If you use these other websites you do it at your own risk.

9\. What rights you have in your personal information and how can you use them

You have the right to ask us not to use your personal information for marketing purposes. We will usually tell you when we collect your personal details if we are planning to use them for marketing purposes or if we plan to pass them to any other organisation for marketing purposes.

You have the right to see information we hold about you, (with some exceptions, which are described in the privacy laws. If you would like a copy of your personal information, you should contact our data protection officer. You will need to pay a processing fee for this service.

10\. How we can make changes to this privacy policy

We may update this privacy policy from time to time so you may want to check it each time you give us personal information or use our websites.

11\. How to contact us about this privacy policy

We welcome your questions, comments and requests about this privacy policy. Please contact our data protection officer using the Contact page.

Updated on 17th July 2016
